onthehouse.com.au 2012-11-23

# Privacy Policy - onthehouse.com.au

onthehouse.com.au ("onthehouse") respects the privacy of your personal information. onthehouse is subject to Privacy Legislation, including the National Privacy Principles ("NPPs") under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), The Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act (1988) and contractual requirements relating to Privacy pursuant to a number of State and Territory Government Licence Agreements. A copy of the National Privacy Principles are available for your perusal at our premises or you may access a copy from the Office of the Federal Privacy Commissioner. The following Privacy Policy outlines the type of information that is collected by onthehouse and how we use and protect that information. 

## 1\. WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Personal information is any information or an opinion, whether true or not, which identifies an individual (includes health information and sensitive information). When personal information concerns certain matters it is considered sensitive information. Sensitive information is information or opinion about an individuals:

  * membership of a political association; 
  * racial or ethnic origin; 
  * health or disability; 
  * membership of a professional or trade association or membership of a trade union; 
  * political opinions; 
  * religious beliefs, affiliations or philosophical beliefs; 
  * criminal record; 
  * sexual preferences or practices.

## 2\. WHO DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY TO?

onthehouse collects personal information from a variety of sources. This privacy policy applies to the following personal information collected by onthehouse:

  * Registration information required to utilise the sell your property facility or email alert service; 
  * Information as requested by onthehouse to complete surveys and enter competitions; 
  * Your IP address; 
  * Cookies and applets;
  * Information sourced from State and Territory Government Land Authorities;
  * Information sourced from Real Estate Agents.

This privacy policy does not apply to parties that may be linked or associated with our website. Those website owners are responsible for the privacy of the information they collect and should be contacted directly for details of their privacy policies.

## 3\. HOW ONTHEHOUSE COLLECTS PERSONAL INFORMATION

Generally, onthehouse will collect personal information directly from you, when you deal with onthehouse online or by email. onthehouse may also collect personal information through various licence agreements with State Government providers and from information provided by Real Estate Agents.

The type of personal information that onthehouse collects depends on the circumstances of collection and on the type of service you request from onthehouse. The particular purpose for which personal information is collected by onthehouse is generally either specified or reasonably apparent at the time the information is collected. onthehouse usually collects information such as your name, address, contact number, occupation, gender, date of birth and email address. It is not onthehouse's general practice to collect sensitive information and we will only collect sensitive information with your consent.

## 4\. HOW ONTHEHOUSE USES PERSONAL INFORMATION 

onthehouse uses personal information for the primary purpose for which it was collected, or for secondary purposes which are related to the primary purpose. Generally, onthehouse uses personal information for the following purposes:

  * to communicate with you; 
  * to assist in the management and improvement of services, including analysis of future client needs; 
  * to provide products and services that have been requested; 
  * to identify ownership of properties advertised on our website; 
  * to undertake marketing activities; and 
  * to comply with any laws.

### Advertisers 

If you are an advertiser on www.onthehouse.com.au your information is held confidentially in a secure (see security) database. Some of your information will be published in your advertisement, in accordance with your instructions and for the period during which your advertisement is active. Your information is only accessible for alterations by you in your capacity as advertiser or by approved onthehouse staff. It is the advertiser's responsibility to ensure that their details on the onthehouse website are current and correct. 

Security & Scam Alert: Do not provide your log in details to anyone in response to email or phone requests.   

### Privately Advertised Property Enquiries

If you have submitted your details to inquire about a privately advertised property, the information may be accessed and reviewed by authorised onthehouse staff and is passed onto the advertiser of the property. If you do not wish for your information to be passed on, please do not complete our online inquiry forms. 

### Licensed Agent Advertised Properties

When completing an online form to inquire about a property for sale from a licensed real estate agency, the information provided may be accessed and reviewed by our authorised onthehouse staff and may be passed on to the licensed real estate agency. The information that you provide is given to the licensed real estate agency to allow them to contact you in relation to the supply of information and viewing of the property. The licensed real estate agency is required to follow their own privacy guidelines with your information once received from onthehouse. If you do not wish for your information to be passed on, please do not complete our online inquiry forms. 

## 5\. WHAT HAPPENS IF AN INDIVIDUAL DOES NOT PROVIDE PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you do not provide the personal information onthehouse requests, it may not be able to provide you with the relevant products or services.

## 6\. ONTHEHOUSE MAY DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION

onthehouse may disclose your personal information for the purpose which was either specified or reasonably apparent at the time when the information was collected. Depending on the circumstances, onthehouse may disclose personal information to:

  * its service providers and specialist advisers; 
  * advertisers of goods or services on the onthehouse website; 
  * private or agent property sellers seeking to sell a property; 
  * any person with a lawful entitlement to obtain the information;

If onthehouse engages a third party contractor to perform services which involves handling personal information, the contractor will be subject to the same privacy obligations as onthehouse to protect your personal information. onthehouse will also take reasonable steps to prohibit the contractor from using personal information, except for the purposes for which it was supplied.

## 7\. DIRECT MARKETING AND PRIVACY

onthehouse may periodically use the personal information it collects about you to assist identifying particular products and services which it believes may be of interest and benefit to you. onthehouse may then contact you to let you know about these products and services and how they may benefit you.

If you do not want to receive any of this information, you should contact onthehouse immediately.

## 8\. ACCURACY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If onthehouse has accurate personal information about you, it enables onthehouse to provide the best possible service.

onthehouse will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it collects, uses and discloses is accurate, complete and up to date. Please advise onthehouse as soon as possible if the personal information held is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. onthehouse will take reasonable steps to ensure your personal information is corrected.

## 9\. SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

onthehouse will take reasonable steps to ensure your personal information is stored in a secure environment protected from unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. onthehouse uses industry standard safeguards to ensure the security of personal information through physical, electronic and managerial procedures. When onthehouse no longer requires personal information, it will safely destroy the information and delete it from its systems.

## 10\. ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION

You may request access to any of the personal information onthehouse holds about you. Upon written request, onthehouse will provide you with access to the personal information it holds about you, unless there is an exemption which applies under the Privacy Act.

Your request for access will be dealt with in a reasonable time. onthehouse may charge you a fee to cover the reasonable cost of retrieval and the supply of the information to you.

If onthehouse refuses your request for access, it will provide you with reasons for the refusal.

## 11\. TRANSFERRING PERSONAL INFORMATION OVERSEAS

Sometimes onthehouse will transfer information to persons outside of Australia. By giving us your personal information, you consent to the disclosure of this information.

## 12\. HOW TO CONTACT ONTHEHOUSE

If you wish to gain access to or correct your personal information or make a complaint about a breach of your privacy, you should contact us.

Our contact details are available on our website: http://www.onthehouse.com.au/contact_us/ 

onthehouse will respond to your query or complaint as soon as possible.   

onthehouse reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. onthehouse will notify any changes by posting an updated version of the Privacy Policy on the website.

_Based on information provided by and with the permission of the Western Australian Land Information Authority (2012) trading as Landgate._
